# Vishvjitsinh(Vish) Ravalji

# Front-End Web Developer

Montreal QC, Canada | vishvajitravalji@gmail.com | +1-514-918-7149 |



in Linkedin



Portfolio



**Github** 

#### **SUMMARY**

Junior Web Developer with around 1 plus years of experience in the field of Web development. Experience in Design and Development of responsive websites and SaaS. Extensive knowledge of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React and Bootstrap. Good in OOPs concept and basic knowledge of Back-end, AWS and Bigdata technologies.

#### **SKILLS**

Experience with: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6, Bootstrap4, React, JSON

Knowledge of: PHP, Spring MVC, Java, Scala, WordPress, HDFS, Spark, Kafka, Tableau, Git/GitHub

Query engine and databases: MySQL, H2, Hive HUE, AWS Athena

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# **Web Developer Intern**

FANIQUE (Toronto, Canada) Upcoming: Sept 2021 - Dec 2021

# **Junior Web Developer**

YOTTOL Tech (Anand, India)

Apr 2018 - Apr 2019

#### **Key Deliverables:**

- Developed the web-based applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap and WordPress.
- Created and maintained mutual fund management platform that enabled our internal analytics team to increase reporting speed.
- Made changes to existing web pages according to the feedback received from the end users or
- In some cases, changes are also made in order to update the applications compatibility with the latest operating systems.
- Managed database in MySQL and H2.

# **EDUCATION**

#### **Post Graduation in Big Data Development**

MCIT (Montreal, Canada) Aug 2020 - July 2021

## Post Graduation in Full Stack JAVA Development

MCIT (Montreal, Canada) July 2019 – June 2020

#### **Bachelors in Computer Science**

GTU (Vadodara, India) Aug 2014 - July 2018

GPA: 3.7

#### **CERTIFICATION**

Udemy - React - The Complete Guide

Clever Programmer - Web Development Bootcamp 2021

**Udemy -** Building an E-Commerce Store Using Java Spring Framework

**Udemy -** The Complete 2021 Web Development Bootcamp

# PROJECTS (Portfolio)

#### Job filter tool SaaS

#### https://cutt.ly/fmLPnjE

- Implemented a responsive web tool using JavaScript ES6.
- transformed JSON data.
- Skill: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JSON

# ETL pipeline of GBFS(BIXI) data

#### https://cutt.ly/AmLI274

- Implemented an automatic ETL pipeline for JSON data files of BIXI.
- Download and transformed JSON files to CSV and write them on the HDFS.
- Used Hive JDBC to execute a cross join between your two external tables and load data into the final table.
- Skill: Scala, Spark Streaming, kafka, Zookeeper, SQL, Hive, HDFS, Hadoop, Parquet and Avro

## **Task Management System**

# https://cutt.ly/MmLOnLJ

- Build a full-stack web app to allow users to do CRUD operations.
- It's managed by Leader, Member and Admin.
- Skill: Java, Spring, MVC, Maven, JSP, H2 DB

#### **Automated Wheel-Chair**

- Completed project on Automated wheel chair that allows handicapped person to operate from mobile device.
- Worked on microcontrollers such as Raspberry Pi and Arduino
- Skill: Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS and IoT